CHARLIE CARR

CONTACT

ADDRESS

New York, NY

PHONE

(856) 745-8351

EMAIL

charliecarr4@gmail.com

LINKS

charlie-carr.com

<u>linkedin.com/in/charliecarr4</u> github.com/CharlesCarr

SOFTWARE SKILLS

HTML5

CSS3

JavaScript (ES6+)

Git

GitHub

React.js (In Progress)

SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT EXPERIENCE & PROJECTS

Full Stack Coding Bootcamp, Wcoding

Seoul, South Korea

Sep 2019 — Dec 2019

- Graduated from full stack web development coding bootcamp in global classroom setting with Korean and international students. Three month intensive all day course with Korean company taught in English
- Completed web-based application projects both independently and in team environment using both front-end and back-end software development languages (HTML, CSS, JavaScript, PHP, MySQL)

Park City, Utah Hotel Website

I started this project with the goal of creating a website that required client-side form validation. From my prior experience working at Oracle in hospitality tech and being an avid skiler, I came up with the idea to apply this in a hotel booking form in Park City, Utah. A few areas of focus for this project include:

- · Client-side Form Validation with Vanilla JavaScript using Regex
- · Interaction with OpenWeatherAPI to display live local weather data
- · Interaction with Google Maps API to display map of Park City
- · Animated Image Carousel using CSS and Vanilla JS with timer and click event

Rock, Paper, Scissors Web App

I built a user vs. computer Rock, Paper, Scissors game for fun to practice Vanilla JavaScript. Originally, this was a single game but later I added a round tracker to allow for more competition and to play the first to 3 round wins. A few areas of focus for this project include:

- · Allowing the user to select a button for Rock, Paper, Scissors
- $\boldsymbol{\cdot}$ Generating a random number to represent the computer selection
- Tracking the round score and ending the game with new UI to show a winner and prompt a new game

Tesla Company Landing Page Clone

I built this Tesla landing page clone to test my development skills by taking a set design and replicating it to a high quality level. A few areas of focus for this project include:

- · Responsive, mobile-first design using media queries
- CSS animations using keyframes
- · Hamburger Menu with JavaScript
- · Deeper dive in positioning with Flexbox

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Sales Development Representative, Blend

New York, NY

Jul 2021 — Oct 2021

- Ramped quickly in remote environment and consistently outperformed quota in generating well qualified, outbound opportunities for sales team
- Due to churn on team, successfully covered two territories for two different lender segments targeting C-level finance, sales, and technology leaders
- Effectively demoed the Blend platform explaining different products and use cases for the cloud-based digital lending platform. Video demos were used as high quality examples for future onboarding classes
- · Left position at Blend to make a career shift to pursue software development

Jul 2020 — Jul 2021

- Generated well qualified, outbound opportunities for west coast sales team for all segments (corporate, enterprise, strategic) for ML-based, cloud-native DLP platform - targeting C-level IT and InfoSec leaders
- Consistently achieved sales quota. Generated over \$130k in closed won business through self sourced outbound opportunities - avg. deal size = \$7k
- Selected by CEO to take on new segment for company in full AE closing role (while maintaining all SDR duties and quota) - full sales cycle, prospect to close - top performer in new segment in ARR, with one multi-integration deal
- Effectively demoed the Nightfall ML DLP platform (without SE assistance)
 explaining a technical product of ML detection, multiple different SaaS integrations, live UI of workflows for prospects

Account Development Representative, BetterCloud

New York, NY

Mar 2020 — May 2022

- Successfully onboarded remotely during pandemic lockdown to support west coast corporate sales team in outbound prospecting for SaaSOps platform, targeting C-level IT and InfoSec leaders
- On track to exceed quota in first fully ramped month but time was cut short due to pandemic company wide layoffs - 3 opportunities in first week of May, 8 was goal for full month

Business Development Representative, Oracle

Columbia, MD

Aug 2018 — Sep 2019

- Developed sales pipeline in key global business accounts for the hospitality vertical's Property Management and Point of Sale solutions
- Consulted with all North American accounts (in addition to global major hotel chain alignment) in achieving targeted tech initiatives through leading cloud-based and on-premise solutions
- Exceeded quota every quarter in role, exceeded revenue quota by 127%
 FY19Q4, 250+% FY19Q3 and awarded org wide BDC of the Month (01/2019) and BDC of the Quarter (FY19Q3)
- Generated over \$700k in closed won business for field sales reps during one fiscal year in role - avg. deal size = \$35k

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Arts in Economics, Hobart College

Geneva, NY

2014 - 2018

- Student Athlete, Division III Hobart College Tennis Team
- · Semester Exchange Student, Lingnan University, Hong Kong (Fall 2017)